Forker, Charles R. mss., 1906-2014 LMC 2847
Lilly Library
Forker, Charles R. mss.
1906-2014
Lilly Library
LMC 2847
7 Boxes
The Forker, Charles R. mss., ca. 1906-2014, consists of the papers of Charles R. Forker and his collection of microfilms and images.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Forker, Professor Emeritus of English at Indiana University Bloomington, was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania on March 11, 1927 and died in Bloomington, Indiana on February 15, 2014. As a child, Forker aspired to be a professional musician; he played the piano. In his teenage years, he began to carry a copy of Shakespeare's sonnets in his pocket. Forker's interest in Shakespeare pervaded his life. He went on to study English at the collegiate level at Bowdoin College, where he focused on cultivating his interests in Shakespeare. He attended Bowdoin College for his first Bachelor's degree, Merton College at Oxford University, where he received his B.A. and his M.A, and Harvard University, where he received his Ph.D. in 1957. Forker went on to hold teaching positions at several universities including: Concordia University, University of Michigan, Indiana University, and the University of Wisconsin. As he continued his intellectual journey, Shakespeare played a role in his research and writing. Forker published ten scholarly books during his career, and his most important work titled, Skull beneath the Skin: The Achievement of John Webster (1986), established his reputation as an authority on Renaissance drama.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: I. Research Materials, II. A/V Materials, and III. Ephemera
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the papers of Charles R. Forker and his collection of microfilms and images related to his research.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 2014
Indiana University -- Faculty; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616--Fiction; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616--Study and teaching; Forker, Charles R.
- Research Materials
  - Research Materials, (20 folders) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes various photograph printouts, photocopied ads, correspondence, articles, newspaper images, Children's Fashion 1900-1950, ed. by Joann Olian, records of photographs.
  - Research Materials, (5 folders) (Box 2)
    Includes Der Matrosenanzug: Kulturgeschicte eines Kleidungsstücks, Robert Kuhn, Bernd Kreutz, Sears & Roebuck catalog and order forms, printed ads.
  - Research Materials, (10 folders) (Box 3)
    Includes includes photocopies of images of children's clothing, ads for children's clothing, and miscellaneous research items.
  - Research Materials, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    Includes children's clothing images; photocopied images and narratives; The History of Men's Underwear, Gary Griffin; and photocopied ads, images, and articles
- A/V Materials
  - Photographs & other A/V, (8 folders) (Box 1)
    Includes photographs, DVDs, CD-ROMs, and USB drive.
  - Photographs, (7 folders) (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
  - Microfilm reels - Eaton's Catalogue (Box 4)
    - 1911 - 1913-14, CLA Reel #0373 (Box 4)
    - SS 1917 - SS 1918, CLA Reel #0376 (Box 4)
    - FW 1932-33 - FW 1934-35, CLA Reel #0387 (Box 4)
    - FW 1934-53 - FW 1936-37, CLA Reel #0388 (Box 4)
    - FW 1936-37 - SS 1938, CLA Reel #0389 (Box 4)
    - SS 1938 - FW 1939-40, CLA Reel #0390 (Box 4)
    - FW 1939-40 - SS 1940, CLA Reel #0391 (Box 4)
    - FW 1941-42 - SS 1943, CLA Reel #0392 (Box 4)
    - SS 1943 - SS 1944, CLA Reel #0393 (Box 4)
  - Microfilm reels (Box 5)
    - Roll #38, 1915 (Box 5)
    - Roll #39, 1915-1916 (Box 5)
    - Roll #40, 1916 (Box 5)
    - Roll #46, 1919 (Box 5)
    - Roll #47, 1919/20 (Box 5)
    - Roll #48, 1920 (Box 5)
    - Roll 49, 1920/21 (Box 5)
    - Roll #50, 1921/22 (Box 5)
    - 1923-24 (Box 5)
    - 1924, Spring/Summer; 1924/25 Fall/Winter Dup. (Box 5)
    - 1925-26 (Box 5)
    - 1926, Spring/Summer; 1926/27 Fall/Winter Dup. (Box 5)
    - 1927/28 (Box 5)
    - 1929/30 (Box 5)
    - 1931/32 (Box 5)
    - 1933/34 (Box 5)
    - Roll #64, 1935/36 (Box 5)
    - Roll #66, 1936-1937 (Box 5)
    - Roll #68, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
    - 1937 Spring, Summer (Box 5)
    - 1938, Spring, Summer, Dup. (Box 5)
    - 1939 Spring, Summer (Box 5)
    - 1940 Spring, Summer (Box 5)
    - 1940 Spring, Summer (Box 5)
    - Roll #72, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
    - Roll #74, 1940-1941 (Box 5)
    - 1940-1941, Roll $#74 (Box 5)
      Empty
    - Roll #76, 1941/42 (Box 5)
    - Roll 78, 1942/43 (Box 5)
    - 1943, Fall (Box 5)
  - Photographs, (5 folders) (Box 6)
- Ephemera
  - Portrait (Box 7)
  - Calendar Art Piece (Box 7)
  - Art Piece, "Toys" (Box 7)
  - Advertisements, copied (Box 7)
  - Advertisements, copied (Box 7)
  - Travel memorabilia (Box 7)
  - Shilling, Charles I reign (Box 4)
    With provenance note